A Finding Aid to the Lloyd Goodrich Papers, 1884-1987, bulk 1927-1987 in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Writings and Research Files, 1884-1987; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 14.5 Linear feet Box 3-17, 38
  - For Publication, 1936-1986; 3.2; Archival Resource Key
    - American Perspectives: The National Self-Image in the Twentieth Century, American Studies Association Book, 1956-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 31-32)
    - "New Art in America," Praeger, 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 33-34)
    - Introduction, Prints of Reginald Marsh, by Norman Sasowsky, 1956-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
    - "Alice Stallknecht Paintings", 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Catalog, Miniatures: Winslow Homer, 1936-1910, The Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
    - Catalog, Adirondack Works by Winslow Homer (1959), 1957-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Foreword, Arshile Gorky by Ethel Schwabacher, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - "The American Vision", circa 1957-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Encyclopedia of American Art, 1957-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 11-15)
    - Foreword, Everett Spruce Portfolio, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Catalog, Fulbright Painters Exhibition (1958), Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - "An Appreciation of the Murals, The Fair Book, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - "The Collection and the Museum," Art in America, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - "The Economics of Contemporary Art," Artists Equity News, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Albert P. Ryder, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - "Form and Images," Art in America, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - "Audubon the Artist", circa 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - "Juliana Force," Notable American Women, 1959-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - General, 1960-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Encyclopedia of World Art, 1960-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Raphael Soyer, 1960-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 27-28)
    - on Albert Pinkham Ryder, Art News, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Review, Winslow Homer, American Artist: His World and His Work, by Albert Ten Eyck Gardner, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Catalog, Ryder Exhibition at Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 3-5)
    - Catalog, New York State Council on the Arts Exhibition, circa 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Art in Maine, Colby College Sesquicentennial, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 7-9)
    - Catalog, Homer in New York State (1963), Storm King Art Center, Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Essay, Drawings of Edwin Dickinson, 1963-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - "The Rebirth of a National Collection," Art in America, 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - "Stuart Davis," Art in America, 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - "Freedom and the Arts," The Art Journal, 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Guide, "Art in the USA and Where to Find It", 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Catalog, Young America, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - "Winslow Homer's America", 1966-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - "Three Centuries of American Art", 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - "The Museum and the Public," Art Voices, 1966-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - on Whitney, Antiques Magazine, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Catalog, Hugo Robus Memorial Exhibit (1966), Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Review/Report, Robert Henri and His Circle, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Catalog, John Marin Exhibition, Knoedler and Co, Inc., 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - on Ryder, Art in America, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Catalog, Benjamin Collection Exhibition, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Edits, Kenneth Hayes Miller, by Lincoln Rothschild, 1967-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 26-28)
    - Catalog, The Collectors' Collections Exhibition (1968), Adelphi University, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - "What's American in American Art," Art in America, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Catalog, American Masters: Art Student League (1967), Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Introduction, Al Hirschfeld, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Catalog, Homer Exhibition, Baltimore Museum of Art, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - The Encyclopedia Americana, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Catalog, Graphics Exhibit (1968), Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Catalog, Lamar Dodd Retrospective, 1969-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Catalog, Whitney Garbisch Collection Exhibition (1969), Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Encyclopedia of World Biography, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - on Harold Sterner, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Catalog, Homer Exhibition, Farnsworth Library and Art Museum, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Reviews, on Homer, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Catalog, What is American in American Art, Knoedler and Co., Inc., 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - on the Arts, American Art Journal, 1971-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - on Soyer, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Review, American Paintings of the Nineteenth Century: Realism, Idealism, and the American Experience, by Barbara Novak, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Catalog, Jerry Bywaters Exhibition (1975), Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - on Juliana Force, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Introduction, The Art and Life of Georgia O'Keeffe, by Jan Garden Castro, 1979-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - "Thomas Eakins," Arts Magazine, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Catalog, Paul Cadmus, Midtown Galleries, 1980-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - on Thomas Hart Benton, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - on Bryson Burroughs, The Arts, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - "A Tribute to Mrs. Miller", 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Catalog, Whitney Retrospective Exhibition, 1982-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Unpublished, 1930-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 14-17)
  - Lectures and Talks, 1933-1983; 3.3; Archival Resource Key
    Found are the drafts, transcripts, and correspondence relating to the planning of Goodrich's lectures and speeches on art, artists, and organizations.
    - Thomas Eakins Lecture, 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - "A Hundred Years of American Landscape Painting", 1937-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - "A Century of American Landscape Paintings," Ipitonga Club, 1938-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Radio Talks, 1938-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - "Criticism and Scholarship", 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - WNYC American Art Festival, 1945-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - "Homer and Eakins: Two Types of Realism", 1948-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 24-26)
    - "The State of American Art," Symposium of Magazine of Art, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - on Homer, New York University Athenaeum, 1948-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - "Juliana Force and American Art," Dayton Art Institute, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - at Ethical Culture Society, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - on Homer, Eakins, and Ryder, 1949-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
    - Corcoran Symposium, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Art Students League Dinner, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - at Skowhegan School Award Dinner, 1950-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Opening Session, Third Woodstock Art Conference, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 10-11)
    - Yale Symposium, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - at American Civil Liberties Union at Town Hall, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - "Mural Painting in the Modern World," Architectural League, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - "The Contemporary Scene," Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - "John Sloan and the Eight," College Art Association at Barbizon Plaza, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - "Art in Democracies," Metropolitan Museum of Art Symposium, 1952-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 17-22)
    - "Art in Modern Society," University of Georgia, 1952-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 23-26)
    - The Club Symposium, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - American Studies Association Symposium, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Kenneth Hayes Miller Exhibition Opening, 1953-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Kuniyoshi Memorial Address, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - at Mount Holyoke College, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Tribute to Reginald Marsh, circa 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - WNYC American Art Festival, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - American Abstract Artitsts' Exhibition Opening, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Barnard College Lecture, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - "Eakins and the Naturalistic Tradition," Pennsylvania State University, 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Columbia University Creative Arts Conference, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - "The Recognizable Image," New York University Symposium, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - on Homer, Eakins, and Ryder, 1956-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - on Homer, Packer Institute, 1956-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "Max Weber," The Jewish Museum, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - "What's American About American Art," Columbia University Seminar on American Civilization, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Arts Festival, North Shore Child Guidance Association of Great Neck, Long Island, New York, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - on Eakins, Packer Institute, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - "Modern Art in Modern Society", 1957-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 6-8)
    - on Homer, 1958-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "Classics of the 19th Century," Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - "Some Ideas on Modern Art," Annual Exhibition of Art by Students of Dalton School, 1958-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Television Broadcasts, 1958-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - "Winslow Homer," The Brooklyn Museum, 1958-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art Lecture Series, 1959-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - "American Art: Realism to Abstraction," WRCA-TV, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - d'Amico Class, Museum of Modern Art, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - "The Artist in American Society", 1960-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 17-19)
    - "American Painting, 1865-1910", 1960-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 19-20)
    - "American Art: Realism to Abstraction," WRCA-TV, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - "Heritage Display of the Young People's Art," Nutley Church, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - on Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - "New Frontiers for Government and the Arts," KPFA, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - "Masters of American Watercolor", 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - on Thomas Eakins, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 26-27)
    - "American Painting: Colonies to Civil War", circa 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Rojtman Seminar, University of Wisconsin, 1963-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 28-29)
    - Lawrence and Barbara Fleischman Exhibition, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - "Role in Government in Art," Philadelphia Museum of Art, Symposium, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - National Art Materials Trade Association, Art Award Dinner, 1963-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - "A Decade of the Armory Show", 1963-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
    - AFA Convention, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Harmonic Club, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Grey Foundation, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Colby College, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - "Winslow Homer and the Sea," Virginia Museum, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - "To Honor the Fine Arts," Stuart Davis Stamp, 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Women's Press Club, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - "A Tribute to Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney," Luncheon Marking the 50th Anniversary of the Founding of the Whitney Studio, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - on Homer, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - "Art Today: What Influences Museums, Collectors and Investors," Statement on Museum Policy for Child Study Association's Symposium, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Abraham Walkowitz Eulogy, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - "Fostering Contemporary Creation: The Role of the Art Museum," Meeting of Arts Commission of Detroit, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Detroit Art Institute's Founders' Society Dinner, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - General, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - "The Municipality and the Arts," Office of Cultural Affairs Conference, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - on Homer, Eakins, and Ryder, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Twentieth Century Fund Luncheon, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - "American Sculpture Today," WPAT, circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Chattahochee Valley Art Association, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - "Total Environment," The Decorators Club, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - "Our National Art Explosion," National Art Materials Trade Association, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - "Landscape," White House Fellows Seminar, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - on John Canady, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Juror Statement, Appalachian Corridors No. 1 (1968), 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - at Women's Patrons Luncheon, Jewish Theological Seminary of America, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - at Telfair Academy, Whitney Collection Exhibition, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - "Art in Modern Society," Lawrence University, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - on Homer, WMAA, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 32-33)
    - on Homer, National Collection of Fine Art, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - "Directions for the National Collection of Fine Arts", 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - at Hackley School, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - "American Painting, 1965-1910", 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - on Eakins and Ryder, Rojtman Seminar, University of Wisconsin, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1-4)
    - on Eakins, Jefferson Medical College, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Harold Weston Memorial, Society for Ethical Culture, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - at Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - "U.S.A., 1910-1930: Orthodoxy and Revolution," Symposium on American Art, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - 78th Annual Dinner Honoring Stewart Klonis, National Arts Club, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - 10th Anniversary Dinner, National Collection of Fine Arts, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - "The New York Art World, 1913-1925: Personal Reminiscences", 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Felicia Meyer Marsh Memorial, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - on Isabel Bishop, Skowhegen Governors Award Dinner, 1982-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Research and Reference Files, circa 1917-1986; 3.4; Archival Resource Key
    Files include research material on artists and those in the art world. Material may include correspondence, printed material, and notes.
    - Alston, Washington, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Bragazzi, Oliver, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Chandler, Winthrop, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Clarke, Thomas (on Scrapbooks), 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 17-18)
    - Cole, Thomas, 1945-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Innes, George, circa 1917-1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Maurer, Alfred Henry, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Miller, Kenneth Hayes, circa 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Mount, William S., circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Nast, Thomas, 1970-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Tracy, J.M., circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Various, 1931-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1-4)
  - General, 1930-1972; 3.5; Archival Resource Key
    Found are notebooks, lists, annotated printed materials, and files titled "ideas".
    - Notebooks, 1940s-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 5-7)
    - Ideas, 1930-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
    - Ideas, Articles, 1930-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Lists, of Publications, 1948-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Annotated Printed Materials, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Notes, General, 1930s-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 13-17)
- Organization and Committee files, 1933-1982; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 14.5 Linear feet Box 17-31, 37
  Folder titles are likely original but have been standardized for clarity.
  Series 4 is arranged in 5 subseries.
  4.1: American Federation of Arts, 1943-1971
  4.2: Association of Art Museum Directors, 1938-1971
  4.3: Carnegie Study in American Art, 1955-1965
  4.4: National Council on the Arts and Government, 1948-1971
  4.5: Other Organizations and Committees, 1933-1982
  Organization and committee files include agendas, correspondence, printed material, meeting minutes, and printed materials regarding Goodrich's service on the boards of arts associations, and organizations and committees, such as the American Federation of Arts, the Association of Art Museum Directors, Carnegie Study in American Art, the National Committee on the Arts and Government, the American Art Research Council, Artists Equity Association, Artist Tenants Association, and others. Many of the documents comment on advocating for government support of the arts and for artists' rights. Other topics covered include affordable housing for artists, forgery and fraud in art, censorship, education about American art at home and abroad, artists' relationships with dealers, and copyright and tariff issues.
  - American Federation of Arts, 1943-1971; 4.1; Archival Resource Key
    Lloyd Goodrich was a director, trustee, and honorary vice president of the American Federation of Arts. Types of materials include agendas, booklets and brochures, by-laws, clippings, correspondence, exhibition lists and schedules, minutes, notes (including for exhibitions), photographs, press releases, reports, and statements.
    - American Traditional Painters, 1960-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Benefit Exhibition - Lists, 1952-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 19-21)
    - Committee on Artistic Freedom, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Committee on Purposes, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Convention 5.50, 1950-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 25-27)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 1-5)
    - Current, 1956-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Executive Committee Meeting 10.31.56, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Exhibition Committee, 1960-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Exhibition for New York State Council on the Arts, "Masters of American Watercolor" - Lists, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Financial Reports, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Foreign Exhibitions Committee, 1954-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 11-12)
    - General Information, 1957-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Holmes Report, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - International Art Exchange Program, 1957-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - "Masters of American Watercolor" 1962, 1961-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Minutes and Agendas, 1952-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 17-19)
    - Minutes, Reports etc., 1964-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
    - 19th Century Exhibition - Lists No. 3, 1952-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - 19th Century Exhibition - Sheets on Artists No. 4, 1952-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Quarterly 1963 Government and Art, Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Statement on Artistic Freedom, 1954-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Traveling Exhibitions, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Trustees, 1957-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Watercolor Exhibtion for Asia, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 10-11)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors, 1938-1971; 4.2; Archival Resource Key